<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<chapter id="introduction_chapter">
	<title>Overview</title>
	<sect1 id="intro_section">
	<title>Introduction</title>
	<para>
		Ahven is a unit test library. It is modeled after
		JUnit framework for Java, but some ideas are also
		taken from another Ada unit test library, AUnit.
	</para>
	<para>
		The purpose of Ahven is to be a small and portable
		unit test library, which works with multiple
		different Ada 95 compilers. Ahven has no
		external dependencies and therefore it is easy
		to build on various platforms.
	</para>
	<para>
		Ahven tries to be compatible with utilities related
		to unit testing. For example, it uses same
		XML format for test results as Java tools.
		This allows easy integration to CruiseControl, Ant,
		and other similar programs.
	</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1 id="license_section">
	<title>License</title>
	<para>
		Ahven is distributed under permissive ISC license (shown below).
	</para>
	<screen><![CDATA[--
-- Copyright (c) 2008 Tero Koskinen <tero.koskinen@iki.fi>
--
-- Permission to use, copy, modify, and distribute this software for any
-- purpose with or without fee is hereby granted, provided that the above
-- copyright notice and this permission notice appear in all copies.
--
-- THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS" AND THE AUTHOR DISCLAIMS ALL WARRANTIES
-- WITH REGARD TO THIS SOFTWARE INCLUDING ALL IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF
-- MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE AUTHOR BE LIABLE FOR
-- ANY SPECIAL, DIRECT, INDIRECT, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES
-- WHATSOEVER RESULTING FROM LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN AN
-- ACTION OF CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION, ARISING OUT OF
-- OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF THIS SOFTWARE.
--]]></screen>
	<para>
		You are allowed to embed Ahven
		into a proprietary commercial application. Only requirement is
		to keep the copyright notice and the permission notice
		in the source code files.
	</para>
	</sect1>

</chapter>
